

Sara Malvar

I'm an engineer with a master and a PhD degree in engineering. I'm passionate about education and science and I currently hold a postdoctoral fellow position at University of São Paulo with the support of the Shell Research Center for Gas Innovation. My main research theme is to find solutions for a more sustainable world using machine learning. Currently, I also work as a mentor, reviewer and instructor at Udacity, Alura and Awari School.

malvar.sara@usp.br

Prazil

in linkedin.com/in/saramalvar

+55 (61) 98115-6756

smalvar.github.io/

github.com/smalvar

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Field Technical Specialist - Data and Storage IBM Brasil

2011 - 2014 Brasilia

Electrical Engineer

VERT TI Solutions

2014 – 2014 Brasília

Assistant Professor

University of Brasilia

2015 – 2016 Brasília

Mentor and Reviewer Udacity

2018 – Present

Nanodegrees

- Data Science Foundations I and II
- Data Scientist
- Al Foundations
- Data Analysis Foundations
- Machine Learning Engineer
- Data Science for Business
- Deep Learning Nanodegree
- Data Visualization with Tableau
- Al for Healthcare

Machine learning instructor

Alura

2019 - Present

Courses

- Predictive models in data: fraud detection
- Data clustering: customer segmentation

Mentor

Awari School

2020 - Present

Courses

- Machine learning and Data science courses

INTERNATIONAL RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Tokyo University (2018)

Research internship

University of Pennsylvania (2019)

Research internship

SKILLS



EDUCATION

Postdoctoral Fellow

University of Sao Paulo

2019 - Present

Theme

Machine learning for seismic inversion

Machine learning for PHB producing bacterial growth optimization

PhD Fluid and Energy Engineering

University of Pennsylvania / Univ. of Sao Paulo 2016 - 2019

MSc Mechanical Sciences

University of Brasilia

2014 - 2015

B.A. Electrical Engineering

University of Brasília

2009 - 2014

AWARDS

Best Undergraduation Project (2014)

EMBRAER / ABCM - Brazilian Association of Mechanical Sciences

Best Scientific Initiation Project (2014)

University of Brasilia

Best Master Theses (Honorable Mention) (2016)

EMBRAER / ABCM - Brazilian Association of Mechanical Sciences

FAMELAB Finalist - Scientific Communication Award (2017)

British Council

Science and Engineering Exchange Program with Latin America - SEELA (2018)

University of Tokyo